Finding Aid for the Jan Williams Collection of Annotated Scores, 1950-1999
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Trythall, Richard Bolero, percussion ensemble Bolero: for 4 percussionists / Richard Trythall. [1979]., 4 ms. scores (18 p. ea.); 30 x 42 cm. (Box 14, Item 183)
  Holograph (Photocopy). At end: "Roma April 6, 79." Duration: ca. 13:30. "Original, don't use"-- Caption. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Trythall, Richard Bolero, percussion ensemble Bolero: for four percussionists / by Richard Trythall New York, NY (271 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024): Hartelu, c1985., 1 score (28 p.) + 4 parts; 24 x 32 cm. (Box 14, Item 184)
  Duration: ca. 15:00. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Inscription on title page. from the composer to percussionist Jan Williams.
- Vigeland, Nils Progress: for solo percussion (1984) / Nils Vigeland. 1984., 13 leaves of ms. music; 28 x 43 cm. (Box 14, Item 185)
  Caption title. Holograph (Photocopy). "Revised 3/84." Duration: 7:25. At end: 11/83 NYC. Performance instructions and other drafts of work ([25]) leaves; 29 cm.) laid in container. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Vigeland, Nils Social etudes: for six percussion players (2 vibraphones, 2 marimbas, glockenspiel, timpani, chimes and 5 gamuts of wood and metal sounds) / Nils Vigeland. 1983., 5 ms. parts; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 14, Item 186)
  Holograph (Photocopy). "For Jan Williams"--Above title in caption. At end of score: NYC - 6/14/83. Some pages oriented vertically. One complete score/part consists of 18 leaves. Scores to be used as parts in combination with separately written parts for musically independent sections. Includes performance instructions. Part of Player 4 (Vibraphone B) wanting. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Typescript note from the composer to Jan Williams (1 leaf) inserted.
- Fulkerson, James In quest of a silence / James Fulkerson. [1977], 1 score (27 p.); 35 cm. (Box 14, Item 187)
  For trombone, vibraphone, and piano. Reproduced from holograph. "Totnes Dec. 1977"--Colophon. Includes performance instructions. Score marked for performance.
- Vigeland, Nils Songs in unknown tongues: for piano, celesta, percussion, and soprano: 3/91 / Nils Vigeland. 1991., 1 ms. score ([11] leaves); 28 x 34 cm. (Box 14, Item 188)
  Holograph (photocopy). For soprano, piano 4 hands, celesta, and percussion. Texts in unknown languages, taken from The gift to be simple: songs, dances and rituals of the American Shakers. Duration: ca. 6:30. At end: Crestwood, 3/91. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Vigeland, Nils Vara: for 2 glockenspiels, 3 vibraphones, 1 xylo/marimba (with low A) and piano / by Nils Vigeland. [1979], 1 ms. score (52 p.); 36 cm. + 6 ms. parts; 22 x 36 cm. (Box 14, Item 189)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). Duration: ca. 23:00. At end of score: 3. XII. 79. Score and parts marked for performance.
- Weddington, Maurice, 1941- Six sung songs: op. 14 / Maurice Weddington. 1969., 1 ms. score (10 p.); 35 cm. (Box 14, Item 190)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). Caption title. For solo percussion. May be performed simultaneously with Six unsung songs for solo violoncello, op. 13. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950 Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny. Alabama-Song; arr. Alabama song / [composed by] Weill; [arr. by] Feldman. 1985., 1 ms. score (12 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 15, Item 191)
  Holograph (Photocopy). For voice, 2 saxophones, trumpet, trombone, marimba, piano, and contrabass. Caption title. Voice part not written in score. Words in English. "1st perf. A[lbright]-K[nox] Gallery, 3/31/85"--Caption. Includes photocopy of p. 11-20 of the Universal Edition vocal score (UE 12889) of excerpt, with Feldman's markings for his arrangement. Marked for performance by conductor Jan Williams.
- Williams, Jan, 1939- Variations, timpani Variations for solo kettledrums / Jan Williams New York: Music for Percussion, c1968., 7 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 15, Item 192)
  Cover title. Reproduced from holograph. Includes performance instructions. At end of score: NYC May 6, 1964. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Wolff, Christian, 1934- Edges / Wolff New York: C.F. Peters, c1969., 1 score (2 leaves); 28 x 39 cm. (Box 15, Item 193)
  Graphic notation. Reproduced from holograph. title page./cover wanting. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Photocopy.
- Wolff, Christian, 1934- Edges: fl., trb., perc. / Wolff New York: C.F. Peters, c1969., 1 score (2 leaves); 21 x 30 cm. (Box 15, Item 194)
  Holograph (Ink). Graphic notation. Title from ms. inscription on leaf of performance instructions. Photocopy of performance instructions from C.F. Peters published score and holograph of graphically-notated score (marked "Perc."). title page./cover wanting.
- Wolff, Christian, 1934- Exercises / [Christian Wolff] [New York: C.F. Peters, c1974], 36 ms. leaves; 28-32 cm. (Box 15, Item 195)
  Title from caption of performance instructions. Reproduced from holograph. For any number of instruments, any number of players. Includes instructions for performance. Includes 5 leaves of ms. notes by Jan Williams. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Consists of 1 complete copy of Exercises 1-18, with duplicates of Exercises 1 (incomplete), 3, 6, 7, 9, 10, 11, 12, and 18. The scores are divided into two groups. The first group, heavily marked for performance, consists of Exercises 1-3, 6-12, and 18. The 2nd group consists of Exercises 1 (incomplete), 3-7, 9-13, 14a, 14b, 15-18.Photocopy.
- Wolff, Christian, 1934- In between pieces: for three players / Christian Wolff New York: C.F. Peters, c1963., 1 ms. score (2, 7 leaves); 21 x 30 cm. (Box 15, Item 196)
  Chance composition; diagrammatic notation. Reproduced from holograph. Includes instructions for performance. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Includes additional, unmarked photocopy.
- Won, Yong Sook Nirvana: for Jan Williams, 1979 / Yong Sook Won. 1979., 8 p. of ms. music; 30 x 42 cm. (Box 15, Item 197)
  Reproduced from holograph. For percussion (1 player). Performance instructions and photos of Asian instruments ([3] leaves); 26 x 37 cm., laid in container. Annotated for performance. Duration: ca. 6:30. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Wuorinen, Charles Spinoff: violin, contrabass, and congas / Charles Wuorinen New York (373 Park Ave. S., New York 10016): C.F. Peters, c1987., 1 score (16 p.); 36 cm. (Box 15, Item 198)
  Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Duration: 6:00. "Composed for Speculum Musicae." At end of score: Charles Wuorinen, New York and Middle Valley, 8 March - 23 April 1983.
- Xenakis, Iannis, 1922-2001 Dmaathen: for oboe and percussion soloists / I. Xenakis Paris ;New York: Editions Salabert, 1976., 1 score (7 p.); 33 x 46 cm. + 1 part (11 p.); 36 cm. (Box 15, Item 199)
  Caption title. Reproduced from holograph. Duration: ca. 10:00. Instructions for fingerings for oboe multiphonics on p. 1. Plate number on percussion part: E.A.S. 17.282. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Xenakis, Iannis, 1922-2001 Dmaathen: for oboe and percussion soloists / I. Xenakis Paris: Editions Salabert, 1976., 1 score (7 leaves); 47 x 63 cm. (Box 15, Item 200)
  Caption title. Reproduced from holograph. Score mounted on cardboard. Instructions for fingerings for oboe multiphonics on p. 1. Duration: ca. 10:00. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Xenakis, Iannis, 1922-2001 Persephassa: pour six percussionistes / Iannis Xenakis Paris ;New York: Salabert, c1970., 1 score (39 p.); 35 cm. (Box 15, Item 201)
  Duration: 20 min. In part, graphic notation. "Instrumental nomenclature and placement of the 6 percussionists" (4 p.) laid in. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Xenakis, Iannis, 1922-2001 Psappha: percussion solo / Iannis Xenakis Paris: Editions Salabert, [c1976], [9] p.; 41 x 62 cm. (Box 15, Item 202)
  Cover title. Graphic notation. Includes instructions for performance in French. "Editions Salabert Rental Library"--Stamp on cover. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Zajonc, Michael, 1956- Frame / Michael Zajonc Buffalo, N.Y.: Factotum Pub., c1992., 1 score (26 p.); 28 cm. (Box 15, Item 203)
  For flute/alto flute, clarinet/bass clarinet, trumpet, trombone, percussion (2 players), and piano. Duration: ca. 10:00. At end of score: 6 April 1982. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Algorithms, no. 3. Version, no. 1 Algo. III, version 1 / [Lejaren Arthur Hiller]. [196-?], 1 score (52 leaves); 34 cm. (Box 15, Item 204)
  Photocopy of holograph? For flute, clarinet, bassoon, trumpet, harp, percussion, violin, violoncello, double bass, and tape recorder. Lacking title page. and 3rd movement. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Johansson, Sven-åke Solostücke für Zion. No. 3 3 Solostücke für Zion.. III / S-å Johansson. 1998., 1 ms. leaf of music; 30 x 42 cm. (Box 15, Item 205)
  Holograph (Photocopy). For solo snare drum. Caption title. Accompanied by Ms. note (2 leaves) from the composer to percussionist Jan Williams.
- Orff, Carl, 1895-1982 Carmina Burana. Vocal score Carmina burana: cantiones profanae, cantoribus et choris cantandae comitantibus instrumentis atque imaginibus magicis / Carl Orff Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne ;New York: Schott Music, [c1956], 141 p.; 31 cm. (Box 15, Item 206)
  "This edition ... is meant for production in schools and in music societies who have no orchestra." Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Sahl, Michael, 1934- For clarinet and percussion: 1965 / Michael Sahl. [1961], 1 ms. score (6 p.); 43 cm. (Box 15, Item 207)
  Caption title. Reproduced from holograph. For clarinet, vibraphone/marimba, and drum set. At end: 7/28/65. McCall, Idaho. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Ni bruit ni vitesse: for piano keys and piano strings / Lukas Foss Paris: éditions Salabert, c1972., 1 score (22 p.); 23 x 32 cm. (Box 15, Item 208)
  Caption title. For 2 pianos and 2 percussionists (playing on the piano strings) or 1 piano, 1 percussionist, and tape; in part, aleatoric. Includes instructions for performance. Duration: 13:30. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Simons, Netty Puddintame / Netty Simons. c1972., 1 score ([2] folded leaves); 36 cm. (Box 15, Item 209)
  For narrator and unspecified group of instruments. Reproduced from holograph. Text: various limericks. Includes 1 ms. leaf of performance notes by Jan Williams. Inscription on title page. from the composer to percussionist Jan Williams.
- Matamoros, Gustavo, 1957- Selections In a fish tank / Gustavo Matamoros. [1991-1996], 1 folder (49 leaves) (Box 15, Item 210)
  Photocopies and computer-generated printouts. Title from printout of email concert notice. Materials used by Jan Williams for the Dec. 4, 1996 concert titled In a fish tank at Merkin Hall, New York City, of multiple pieces by Gustavo Matamoros. Includes printout of email notice of concert (1 leaf) and 3 leaves with start times for pieces, including Pocket change and More or less, or Time is money, from Music on a budget, each with descriptions of actions to be taken by Jan Williams.
- Hodkinson, Sydney Interplay: a histrionic controversy for four musicians / by Sydney Hodkinson. 1966., 1 ms. score (24 p.); 36 cm. (Box 16, Item 211)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). Completed in October 1966. For alto flute doubling piccolo, clarinet doubling alto saxophone, percussion, and double bass. Cover title. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams. Performing notes: p. A22-A24. Duration: ca. 12 min. At end of score: October 1966, Windsor, Ontario, Ann Arbor, Michigan.
- Miroglio, Francis Réfractions / Miroglio. [1968?], 1 ms. score ([7] leaves); 40 x 63 cm. (Box 16, Item 212)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). For flute, violin, percussion, and piano. Includes instructions for performance. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Kolb, Barbara Place settings [Three place settings: for violin, clarinet, double bass, percussion, and narrator / Barbara Kolb]. [1968]., 1 ms. score (13 leaves); 29 x 44 cm. (Box 16, Item 213)
  Holograph (Ozalid copy). Title supplied by cataloger; title page. wanting. At end of score: "Barbara Kolb, February, 1968, New York City." Includes performance notes. Marked for performance by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Moran, Robert, 1937- Bombardments, no. 2 Bombardments, no. 2: percussion ensemble, 1 to 5 players / Robert Moran New York: C.F. Peters, c1966., 5 diagrammatic scores ([1] fold. leaf each); 30 cm. (Box 16, Item 214)
  Cover title. Scores marked for performance, in part by percussionist Jan Williams.
- Vigeland, Nils Octet: original version / Vigeland. [1978]., 1 ms. score (47 leaves); 22 x 28 cm. (Box 16, Item 215)
  Holograph (Photocopy). Title from accompanying envelope. For percussion (glockenspiel, vibraphone, marimba and 2 timpani) [1 player], clarinet (B? and bass), piano, string quartet.
- Vigeland, Nils Octet: 1978: for percussion (glockenspiel, vibraphone, marimba and 2 timpani), clarinet (B? and bass), piano, string quartet / by Nils Vigeland. [1980]., 1 ms. score (72 p.); 22 x 28 cm. + 5 parts; 28-36 cm. (Box 16, Item 216)
  Holograph (Photocopy). At end of score: South Bend, 2/19/78; rev. Dobbs Ferry, 1/80. Score contains numerous corrections and performance markings; some pages replaced by photocopies and additional photocopied pages have been inserted into the original sequence of pages. Parts incomplete: string quartet parts (with duplicate of viola) and percussion; marked for performance. Duration: ca. 17:00. Accompanied by correspondence from Nils Vigeland to Diane and Jan Williams, and from Diane Williams to John Duffy of Meet the Composer (6 leaves ms. and typescript).
- Nørgård, Per, 1932- Mating dance / Per Nørgård. [1977]., 1 ms. score (9 p.); 35 cm. (Box 16, Item 217)
  Photocopy of ms. Caption title. For flute and guitar; score marked by percussionist Erik Jacobsen to be performed by flute and percussion (crotales, marimba, and vibraphone). Includes prefatory leaf of performance instructions for the first version of this work which was titled Returns and was for solo guitar. At end of score: "Kbh. 25/11 - 77". Includes typescript letter (1 leaf) dated Jan. 26, 1979 from Erik Jacobsen to percussionist Jan Williams with an explanation of how the present version came about and performance instructions.
- Mott, David Ceremony, no. 1-2 Ceremony. 1-7 / David Mott. [197-?], 1 ms. score (11 leaves); 36 x 44 cm. (Box 16, Item 218)
  For flute with percussion (1 player). Spine title. Holograph (Ozalid reproduction). Author's signature appears on first leaf of music. Score has been annotated with performance notes for percussionist. Includes 1 leaf of instructions, 3 leaves of performance notes. Ceremony 3 is missing; Ceremony 4 is reproduced four times. Percussion part marked by Jan Williams for performance.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Music for six / Lukas Foss New York: Pembroke Music Co.: C. Fischer, sole selling agents, c1978., 6 parts; 30 cm. (Box 16, Item 219)
  Chance composition for 6 unspecified instruments. "Commissioned by the Philadelphia Composer's Forum." Duration: ca. 15 min. Parts marked for performance by ensemble conducted by Jan Williams.
- Cage, John But what about the noise of crumpling paper ... New York: Henmar Press: C. F. Peters, c1985., 13 leaves; 29 cm. (Box 16, Item 220)
  Includes 2 manuscript leaves of performance instructions by Jan Williams.
- MacBride, David Face: for two drummers New York: American Composers Alliance, 1986., 1 score (ii, 6 pages); 39 cm. (Box 16, Item 221)
  Marked for performance by Jan Williams.
- Roqué Alsina, Carlos, 1941- Themen: per una percussionista, op. 34 Milan: Edizioni Suvini Zerboni, 1974., 1 score (8 pages); 34 x 50 cm. (Box 16, Item 222)
- Bergamo, John Duet undated, 1 manuscript score (5 pages); 33 cm. (Box 16, Item 223)
  Second copy of first movement marked for performance.
- Williams, Jan, 1939- Varitations for four kettledrums undated, 2 pages of performance instructions, 10 leaves of music; 32 cm. (Box 16, Item 224)
  Pencil holograph, includes some sketch material.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Percussion music--Scores; Williams, Jan, 1939- --Archives
Genres
Scores
Associated Material
Separated Material
The following scores without markings were removed from the collection and cataloged to the General Collection:
Adams, John Luther: Five pieces from Coyote builds North America
Bergamo, John: Tanka (1976 copy)
Boone, Charles: Morphosis, percussion quartet
Boyd, Anne: KaKan
Cage, John: Sixteen dances, for soloist and company of 3 (1951)
Cardew, Cornelius: Sextet--The tiger's mind
Carl, Robert: Magic act, 1988, for violin and marimba
Celimli, Evren: Dawnbreaker
Cerro, Emiliano del: At least at death...
Cerro, Emiliano del: Black chamber
Cerro, Emiliano del: Prometida oscuridad (Promised obscurity)
Chadabe, Joel: Interactions (3)
Cope, David: Towers
Di Pietro, Rocco: Annales sans condition
Di Pietro, Rocco: Aria da concerto: Bellini on the moon
Di Pietro, Rocco: Aria per pianoforte
Di Pietro, Rocco: Aria per violoncello
Di Pietro, Rocco: Canto d'azione
Di Pietro, Rocco: Charivari 2000
Di Pietro, Rocco: Melodia
Di Pietro, Rocco: Popular songs
Di Pietro, Rocco: Segue l'arie Donizetti in Buffalo
Duckworth, William: Pitch city
Durko Zsolt: Quattro dialoghi
Eastman, Julius: Tripod
Eberhard, Dennis: Dialogues II
Eisma, Will: Because it is
Eisma, Will: Gezang XXIII for violin and percussion
Eisma, Will: Metselwerk for solo-percussion and orchestra
Elwood, Paul Iserman: Big sky
Ficarelli, Mario: Ensaio (1972)
Foss, Lukas: Airs for Frank O'Hara's angel
Foss, Lukas: Paradigm
Fulkerson, Christopher: The Childermass
Fulkerson, Christopher: Night litany
Fulkerson, James: In quest of a silence
Fulkerson, James: Two activities
Fulkerson, Mary: Unity piece
Furioso, William: Solo encounter
Gann, Kyle: Cherokee songs
Garcia, Orlando Jacinto: Variations on metallic and wooden shades
Garca, Orlando Jacinto: Individual migrations
Gibson, David: Thirteen ways of looking at a blackbird
Goodman, Saul: Scherzo, for percussion
Grana, Edgar David: Songs at sundown
Hand, Mark: Sources
Hatch, Peter Donald: Blunt music
Hiller, Lejaren Arthur: Machine music
Holten, Bo: Wave and cut
Jack,: Nouvelle etude
Johnson, Keith Victor: Music for violin and marimba
Johnston, Ben: Knocking piece II
Karkoff, Ingvar: Concerto for alto saxophone and percussion
Klucevesk, Guy: Caterpillar canon
Komorous, Rudolf: Sladk klovna
Kwiatkowski, Ryszard: xb-132
La Barbara, Joan: Chords and gongs
Lanza, Alcides: Ektenes II
Luciuk, Juliusz: Lirica di timbri per pianoforte
Lylloff, Bent: Places
Macbride, David: Murder by Macbride
Macbride, David: XYWAYZ
Macchia, Salvatore: Dance prelude
Maniel: Folk songs for 4 percussionts and 1 clarinet
Mantel, Mark Douglas: Folk songs, 4 pecussionists...
Mellnas, Arne: Rendez-vous 2
Miranda, Anthony: True image
Miranda, Anthony: Two episodes for solo snare drum
Moore, Edgar J.: Scenario in three movements
Morrell, Todd: Tone row to tone loc toccata
Myhill, John: Astarte
Rimmer, John: Emergence for clarinet and percussion
Rimmer, John: The revelation of increasing complexity, Part I
Rimmer, John: The ring of fire
Rzewski, Frederic: To the earth
Saitta, Carmelo: 2 x 4
Saul, Lewis: Discussions for flute, string quartet, and percussion
Scoville, Margaret: Time out of mind
Siegel, Wayne: Last request for solo percussion
Sierra, Roberto: Invocaciones
Simons, Netty: Puddintame
Skiba, Norman: Zen studies, solo percussion
Smith, Stuart: In common
Stabler, Gerhard: Windows
Stockhausen, Karlheinz: Zyklus
Thomas, John Patrick: Natale
Trythall, Richard: Salute to the Fifties for percussionist and tape
Vigeland, Nils: Trio
Wolman, Ammon: The day the bank came through
Xenakis, Iannis: Rebonds
Young, La Monte: Arabic numeral (any integer)
Additional Guides
All scores in the collection are cataloged in WorldCat and are available in BISON, the online catalog for the University at Buffalo Libraries, by performing a "Title begins with" search under "Jan Williams Collection of Annotated Scores".
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Jan Williams Collection of Images, 1950-1999
Mus. Arc. 2.3
The Jan Williams Collection of Images contain images of various performances and trips made by Jan Williams with accompanying performers and composers. An original gift was received of 321 prints and contact sheets and 54 35mm slides in 2007. An additional gift was received of 173 photographs in 2008.
Morton Feldman Images by Jan Williams, 1974-1979
Mus. Arc. 10.1
The Morton Feldman Images by Jan Williams date from concert tours made by Morton Feldman and the University at Buffalo's Creative Associates in 1974, 1977, and 1979.